[
    {
        "question": "Now the word of the LORD came to Jonah the son of Amittai, saying, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:1",
        "rank": "1,144"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the LORD hurled a great wind upon the sea, and there was a mighty tempest on the sea, so that the ship threatened to break up. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:4",
        "rank": "2,069"
    },
    {
        "question": "And they said to one another, \u201cCome, let us cast lots, that we may know on whose account this evil has come upon us.\u201d So they cast lots, and the lot fell on Jonah. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:7",
        "rank": "2,593"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the men were exceedingly afraid and said to him, \u201cWhat is this that you have done!\u201d For the men knew that he was fleeing from the presence of the LORD, because he had told them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:10",
        "rank": "2,628"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then they said to him, \u201cWhat shall we do to you, that the sea may quiet down for us?\u201d For the sea grew more and more tempestuous. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:11",
        "rank": "2,687"
    },
    {
        "question": "So the captain came and said to him, \u201cWhat do you mean, you sleeper? Arise, call out to your god! Perhaps the god will give a thought to us, that we may not perish.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:6",
        "rank": "2,723"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the mariners were afraid, and each cried out to his god. And they hurled the cargo that was in the ship into the sea to lighten it for them. But Jonah had gone down into the inner part of the ship and had lain down and was fast asleep. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:5",
        "rank": "2,759"
    },
    {
        "question": "And he said to them, \u201cI am a Hebrew, and I fear the LORD, the God of heaven, who made the sea and the dry land.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:9",
        "rank": "3,013"
    },
    {
        "question": "(1) And the LORD appointed(2) a great fish to swallow up Jonah. And Jonah was in the belly of the fish three days and three nights. Footnotes (1) 1:17 Ch 2:1 in Hebrew (2) 1:17 Or *had appointed* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:17",
        "rank": "3,178"
    },
    {
        "question": "He said to them, \u201cPick me up and hurl me into the sea; then the sea will quiet down for you, for I know it is because of me that this great tempest has come upon you.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:12",
        "rank": "3,341"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore they called out to the LORD, \u201cO LORD, let us not perish for this man\u2019s life, and lay not on us innocent blood, for you, O LORD, have done as it pleased you.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:14",
        "rank": "3,351"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then they said to him, \u201cTell us on whose account this evil has come upon us. What is your occupation? And where do you come from? What is your country? And of what people are you?\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:8",
        "rank": "3,383"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nevertheless, the men rowed hard(1) to get back to dry land, but they could not, for the sea grew more and more tempestuous against them. Footnotes (1) 1:13 Hebrew *the men dug in* [their oars] (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:13",
        "rank": "3,452"
    },
    {
        "question": "For you cast me into the deep, into the heart of the seas, and the flood surrounded me; all your waves and your billows passed over me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:3",
        "rank": "3,468"
    },
    {
        "question": "The word reached(1) the king of Nineveh, and he arose from his throne, removed his robe, covered himself with sackcloth, and sat in ashes. Footnotes (1) 3:6 Or *had reached* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:6",
        "rank": "3,556"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the men feared the LORD exceedingly, and they offered a sacrifice to the LORD and made vows. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:16",
        "rank": "3,600"
    },
    {
        "question": "So they picked up Jonah and hurled him into the sea, and the sea ceased from its raging. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:15",
        "rank": "3,621"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jonah went out of the city and sat to the east of the city and made a booth for himself there. He sat under it in the shade, till he should see what would become of the city. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:5",
        "rank": "4,648"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then I said, \u2018I am driven away from your sight; yet I shall again look upon your holy temple.\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:4",
        "rank": "4,792"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now the LORD God appointed a plant(1) and made it come up over Jonah, that it might be a shade over his head, to save him from his discomfort.(2) So Jonah was exceedingly glad because of the plant. Footnotes (1) 4:6 Hebrew *qiqayon*, probably the castor oil plant; also verses 7, 9, 10 (2) 4:6 Or *his evil* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:6",
        "rank": "5,324"
    },
    {
        "question": "And he issued a proclamation and published through Nineveh, \u201cBy the decree of the king and his nobles: Let neither man nor beast, herd nor flock, taste anything. Let them not feed or drink water, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:7",
        "rank": "5,701"
    },
    {
        "question": "The waters closed in over me to take my life; the deep surrounded me; weeds were wrapped about my head (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:5",
        "rank": "5,761"
    },
    {
        "question": "at the roots of the mountains. I went down to the land whose bars closed upon me forever; yet you brought up my life from the pit, O LORD my God. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:6",
        "rank": "6,039"
    },
    {
        "question": "but let man and beast be covered with sackcloth, and let them call out mightily to God. Let everyone turn from his evil way and from the violence that is in his hands. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:8",
        "rank": "6,322"
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who pay regard to vain idols forsake their hope of steadfast love. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:8",
        "rank": "6,651"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who knows? God may turn and relent and turn from his fierce anger, so that we may not perish.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:9",
        "rank": "6,686"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the LORD spoke to the fish, and it vomited Jonah out upon the dry land. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:10",
        "rank": "6,943"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the sun rose, God appointed a scorching east wind, and the sun beat down on the head of Jonah so that he was faint. And he asked that he might die and said, \u201cIt is better for me to die than to live.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:8",
        "rank": "7,112"
    },
    {
        "question": "But when dawn came up the next day, God appointed a worm that attacked the plant, so that it withered. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:7",
        "rank": "7,156"
    },
    {
        "question": "But God said to Jonah, \u201cDo you do well to be angry for the plant?\u201d And he said, \u201cYes, I do well to be angry, angry enough to die.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:9",
        "rank": "7,281"
    },
    {
        "question": "When my life was fainting away, I remembered the LORD, and my prayer came to you, into your holy temple. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:7",
        "rank": "7,351"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the LORD said, \u201cYou pity the plant, for which you did not labor, nor did you make it grow, which came into being in a night and perished in a night. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:10",
        "rank": "7,593"
    },
    {
        "question": "So Jonah arose and went to Nineveh, according to the word of the LORD. Now Nineveh was an exceedingly great city,(1) three days\u2019 journey in breadth.(2) Footnotes (1) 3:3 Hebrew *a great city to God* (2) 3:3 Or *a visit was a three days\u2019 journey* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:3",
        "rank": "8,370"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cArise, go to Nineveh, that great city, and call out against it the message that I tell you.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:2",
        "rank": "10,383"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore now, O LORD, please take my life from me, for it is better for me to die than to live.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:3",
        "rank": "10,780"
    },
    {
        "question": "And he prayed to the LORD and said, \u201cO LORD, is not this what I said when I was yet in my country? That is why I made haste to flee to Tarshish; for I knew that you are a gracious God and merciful, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love, and relenting from disaster. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:2",
        "rank": "11,349"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the LORD said, \u201cDo you do well to be angry?\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:4",
        "rank": "12,528"
    },
    {
        "question": "When God saw what they did, how they turned from their evil way, God relented of the disaster that he had said he would do to them, and he did not do it. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:10",
        "rank": "12,529"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the word of the LORD came to Jonah the second time, saying, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:1",
        "rank": "12,851"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jonah began by going a day's journey into the city, proclaiming, \"Forty more days and Nineveh will be overthrown.\"",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:4",
        "rank": "12,932"
    },
    {
        "question": "saying, \u201cI called out to the LORD, out of my distress, and he answered me; out of the belly of Sheol I cried, and you heard my voice. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:2",
        "rank": "13,405"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then Jonah prayed to the LORD his God from the belly of the fish, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:1",
        "rank": "13,536"
    },
    {
        "question": "But Jonah rose to flee to Tarshish from the presence of the LORD. He went down to Joppa and found a ship going to Tarshish. So he paid the fare and went down into it, to go with them to Tarshish, away from the presence of the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:3",
        "rank": "13,848"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cArise, go to Nineveh, that great city, and call out against it, for their evil(1) has come up before me.\u201d Footnotes (1) 1:2 The same Hebrew word can mean *evil* or *disaster*, depending on the context; so throughout Jonah (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 1:2",
        "rank": "14,133"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the people of Nineveh believed God. They called for a fast and put on sackcloth, from the greatest of them to the least of them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 3:5",
        "rank": "14,311"
    },
    {
        "question": "But I with the voice of thanksgiving will sacrifice to you; what I have vowed I will pay. Salvation belongs to the LORD!\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 2:9",
        "rank": "14,575"
    },
    {
        "question": "And should not I pity Nineveh, that great city, in which there are more than 120,000 persons who do not know their right hand from their left, and also much cattle?\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:11",
        "rank": "15,348"
    },
    {
        "question": "But it displeased Jonah exceedingly,(1) and he was angry. Footnotes (1) 4:1 Hebrew *it was exceedingly evil to Jonah* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jonah 4:1",
        "rank": "15,715"
    }
]